RÉSUMÉ

John Krug

12/01/1963

jh.krug@gmail.com

Calle Adrián López Iriarte 27 Padul, Granada, Andalusia, España

+34 644 334 591.

I never answer calls from unrecognized numbers (too much spam/scam). Please message first using email, Signal, or Telegram and we can get together.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jhkrug

Twitter: https://twitter.com/jhkrug

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a widely experienced information technology professional, with, so far, a 30 year career. I have worked in the development, systems integration, deployment, data management, and technical documentation fields, often in leadership roles and in the public utility, private business and higher education areas. Most recently, I have been doing some technical writing using a docs-as-code approach and thoroughly enjoying it.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Consultant, Independent, May 2017 - Present

Since moving to Spain I have worked mainly on behalf of the University of Leeds. I developed a set of Alma and Primo analytics training materials that their staff could use. We agreed that the material could be Creative Commons licensed. The training materials website at https://libtics.org is the result of that work.

The training materials developed are hosted using Netlify, they are coded using asciidoc markup and processed into libtics.org using Antora. The materials consist of documentation and accompanying video material. The source is at https://gitlab.com/libtics.

In 2018, I helped organize and presented at a workshop on Alma Analytics for UK Ex Libris users.

Systems and Analytics Manager, Lancaster University Library, *April 2002 - March 2017*

I spent 15 happy years at Lancaster University Library starting as the Library Systems Coordinator. The first role was the implementation of the Aleph library management system. This was used to replace a custom in-house system. Other Ex Libris systems were implemented and integrated; Metalib and SFX from 2004, Primo from 2010 and the new cloud based library management system, Alma from 2012/13.

For IGeLU[1] and ELUNA[2] I established the first Analytics working group[3]. The group was established to work through issues with Ex Libis in relation to analytics products they provided. This involved coordinating the effort of about 14 library professionals around the world in many timezones.

Key achievements: Implementing Alma and Primo, ILM Level 5 Award in leadership and management. First coordinator of the IGeLU and ELUNA Analytics working group. Lancaster University staff award for outstanding achievement.

Technical Director, Xinetica Ltd, 1999 - April 2002

Along with a small group of colleagues we had a go at starting and running an information systems integration consultancy. I did consultancy work and systems implementation for ASDA in Leeds. Also, for the Financial Services Authority, the governments financial services regulator, in London. We did well for a few years then the first internet bubble collapse and internal divisions closed us down.

Protek Ltd, Technical Consultant, 1996-1998

I worked mainly at North West Water supporting Unix (IBMs AIX) hardware and software infrastructure and developing software on their behalf.

Barclays de Zoet Wedd, Systems Administrator, 1995-1996

I worked supporting Sun Microsystems Unix workstations running a variety of financial trading software for the foreign exchange derivatives desk.

NTSC, Technician, 1992-1994

I worked to support the NTSC[4] efforts in promoting the uses of parallel processing using the INMOS transputer. I followed up on my M.Sc. dissertation work with further work with British Steel in computer vision.

British Army, Royal Artillery, 1983-1986



EDUCATION

1990-1991 - University of Sheffield, M.Sc. Software Systems Technology

1985-1989 - Open University (UK), a variety of undergraduate courses at different levels, mainly mathematics and computing. Never got round to finishing off an undergraduate degree, but the results were good enough over the years to get a place on a M.Sc. at the University of Sheffield.

SKILLS

I have used and integrated many information technologies, databases, networks, and tools over the years. I am very familiar with Unix/Linux and the shell. Likewise, I have programmed in many languages over the years (Assembler, C, OCCAM, SQL, Lua, Python, Shell, etc., etc.). I have written much technical material and documentation. Much of this work has been to do with data wrangling of one sort or another. Many times, I have learned new technologies and used and implemented them where I have been working.

I have worked both independently and closely with others in large and small organizations and teams, often remotely across the world and timezones. I have been an employee, a director/owner and a manager on different occasions.

REFERENCES

From Masud Khokhar:

https://john.libtics.org/public/references/MK-JK-ref.pdf

From David Summers:

https://john.libtics.org/public/references/DS-JK-ref.pdf

FOOTNOTES

- 1 International Group of Ex Libris Users
- 2 Ex Libris Users of North America
- 3 Analytics SIWG at https://igelu.org/products-and-initiatives/communities-of-practice/analytics/
- 4 National Transputer Support Centre in Sheffield. A body established with UK government funding to promote the concepts of parallel processing using the INMOS Transputer. The Transputer was a UK developed microprocessor with facilities to enable it to work in a massively parallel fashion with other transputers.

http://www.chilton-computing.org.uk/inf/transputers/p002.htm

OTHER

I have a, very, occasional blog, currently at https://john.libtics.org.